Ilie Sarpe

PhD Student

⊠ sarpeilie@dei.unipd.it iliesarpe.github.io

Last update: May 2022

ABOUT ME

I am a third year PhD student in Computer Engineering under the supervision of Prof. Fabio Vandin. My research interests largely focus on the development of algorithms for the analysis of massive temporal networks. In particular I am currently developing data mining algorithms for collecting patterns (e.g., motifs) from large temporal networks, such algorithms need to be scalable and efficient since extracting such patterns may be unfeasible on large temporal networks with currently available techniques. I am thus focused especially on sampling-based algorithms with provable theoretical guarantees.

EDUCATION

PhD Student

Oct 2019 - Present

University of Padova, Italy Department of Information Engineering

TOPIC: Efficient and Rigorous Techniques for the Analysis of Large Temporal Networks

ADVISOR: Prof. Fabio Vandin

M.S. in Computer Engineering

Oct 2017 - Sep 2019

University of Padova, Italy Department of Information Engineering THESIS TITLE: Mining Motifs in Temporal Networks

GRADE: 110/110 e lode (summa cum laude)

ADVISOR: Prof. Fabio Vandin

B.S. in Computer Engineering

Oct 2014 - Sep 2017

University of Padova, Italy Department of Information Engineering THESIS TITLE: Statistical Correlation between Alignment-free and Edit Distance

Measures

Grade: 104/110

ADVISOR: Prof. Matteo Comin

ACADEMIC APPOINTMENTS

VISITING PHD STUDENT Oct 2022 - Jan 2023

Department of Computer Science, KTH, Stockholm (Sweden), advised by Prof. Aristides Gionis.

TEACHING

TEACHING ASSISTANT

2018 - 2021

Big Data Computing, Department of Information Engineering, University of Padova

Teaching Assistant

2017 - 2019

Tutorato Formativo, Department of Information Engineering, University of Padova

Publications

* denotes equal contribution.

† denotes contact author.

Diego Santoro* and Ilie Sarpe*†, ONBRA: Rigorous Estimation of the Temporal Betweenness Centrality in Temporal Networks, Accepted at ACM The Web Conference 2022 (WWW 2022). (Acceptance rate 17.7%)

Ilie Sarpe and Fabio Vandin, ODEN: Simultaneous Approximation of Multiple Motif Counts in Large Temporal Networks, Accepted at the 30th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM 2021). Selected presentation (only a small number of works were selected for live presentation). (Acceptance rate 21.7%)

Ilie Sarpe and Fabio Vandin, PRESTO: Simple and Scalable Sampling Techniques for the Rigorous Approximation of Temporal Motif Counts, Accepted at the 2021 SIAM International Conference on Data Mining (SDM21). (Acceptance rate 21.15%)

Talks at International Conferences

29th April 2021 PRESTO: Simple and Scalable Sampling Techniques for the Rigorous Approximation of Temporal Motif Counts. 2021 SIAM International Conference on Data

Mining (SDM21), April 29 - May 1, 2021, Virtual Event. 4th November 2021 ODEN: Simultaneous Approximation of Multiple Motif Counts in Large Temporal

> Networks. 30th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM 2021), 1 - 5 November 2021, Queensland (Australia), Virtual

Event.

28th April 2022 ONBRA: Rigorous Estimation of the Temporal Betweenness Centrality in Temporal Networks. ACM The Web Conference 2022 (WWW 2022), 25-29 April 2022,

Lyon (France), Virtual Event.

Invited Talks

Motifs in Temporal Networks Definitions, Algorithms and Applications. Invited lecture for the Learning from Networks M.Sc. course, Department of Information Engineering, University of Padova, Italy.

Fellowships and Awards

Oct 2022 SoBigData Transnational Access (known as TNA) support for short term visits.

Oct 2019 - Dec 2022 PhD Fellowship from "Department of Information Engineering (DEI)", University of Padova, Italy

> Award for scientific degrees, award given to the best 500 students of scientific 2017 degrees, University of Padova, Italy

> "Mille e una lode", award for the top 5% students of the academic year 2016, 2017 University of Padova, Italy

> 2016 "Mille e una lode", award for the top 5% students of the academic year 2015, University of Padova, Italy

OTHER INFORMATION

RECOMB 2020, KDD 2020, ICDM 2020, WWW 2021, ECML-PKDD 2021, ICDM Conference Reviewer

2021, WSDM 2022, WWW 2022, KDD 2022, ICDM 2022

Journal Reviewer Journal of Graph Algorithms and Applications.

> PRIN Project n. 20174LF3T8 AHeAD (Efficient Algorithms for Harnessing Net-**Projects** worked Data), MIUR Italy. "SID 2020: RATED-X", University of Padova, Italy.

SoBigData TNA.

Programming Experience C++, C, Java, Python, MATLAB, SQL, NoSQL, Bash, LATEX

Apache Spark, IBM ILOG CPLEX Programming Frameworks

Native Italian and Romanian Speaker, B2 English Languages

Software Packages Open-source software packages:

> PRESTO: an efficient sampling algorithm for estimating the count of a temporal motif in a temporal network. https://github.com/VandinLab/PRESTO.

> \circ ODEN: and efficient sampling algorithm for estimating the counts of multiple temporal motifs sharing a common topological structure. https://github. com/VandinLab/odeN.

> o ONBRA: an efficient algorithm for estimating the temporal betweenness centrality of the various nodes in a temporal network under two criteria for the paths considered. https://github.com/iliesarpe/onbra.

22nd December 2021

Selected talk